newgisticsfulfillment.com 2017-07-12

# PRIVACY POLICY - Newgistics

Effective September 1, 2016 

Newgistics, Inc. (“Newgistics”, “We”, “Us”, or “Our”) has created this privacy policy (“Policy”) to explain why we collect particular information and how we will protect your personal privacy within our Web sites. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. The following document discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for www.newgistics.com, www.tacitknowledge.com, ncommerce.com and our services returnscenter.smartlabel.com and www.shipmentmanager.com (collectively, the “Site”).

Please read this Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Site. By accessing or using this Site, you agree to this Policy. This Policy may change from time to time (see Changes to this Policy). Your continued use of this Site after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the Policy periodically for updates.

EU-U.S. Privacy Shield 

Newgistics, Inc. (and its subsidiary company Tacit Knowledge Inc.) participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Newgistics, Inc. is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List.   
[<https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>]

Newgistics, Inc. is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to third parties acting as agents on its behalf. Newgistics, Inc. complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Newgistics, Inc. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Newgistics, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>], you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework

Newgistics complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from Switzerland. [Participant] has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Newgistics’s certification, please visit <https://safeharbor.export.gov/swisslist.aspx>.

What Information We Collect 

Newgistics is the sole owner of the information collected on the Site. The Site does not collect personal information about you except when you or our clients specifically and knowingly provide it. Such personal information may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, home address and phone number. We use this information to fulfill your request or respond to product or service information you or our clients requested. We may also collect information that is about you but individually does not identify you, such as your location or company name, and/or about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access the Site and usage details.

We may collect this information directly from you when you provide it to us or automatically as you navigate through the Site. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies. We may also collect this information from third parties, for example, our clients.

Information Sharing

We will not disclose personal information without your express permission. Except as expressly stated in this Policy, we will not sell, share or rent personal information to any other companies.

However, by using the Site you agree that all information connected to a specific return or delivery can be shared with the retailer involved in the return or delivery transaction. In addition, we may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Certain personal information may be disclosed if we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or there is a sale of all or a portion of our assets whether as a going concern or as a part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding in which personal information held by us about our Site is among the assets transferred. If such an event occurs, we will provide notice on our Site of any change in ownership.

Children under the Age of 13

Our Site is for adults and usage by children is not intended. We do not seek to collect personal information about children through our site. No one under age 13 may provide and information to the site. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Site or through any of its features, or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13, we will delete the information as soon as we discover it and will not use it for any purpose, nor will we disclose it to third parties. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at the contact information set forth below. 

Exception to Privacy Policy

In certain situations, Newgistics may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also provide personal information about users when required by law or a governmental authority including, without limitation, under request of subpoena or similar legal process. We may also disclose personal information when we believe in good faith upon advice of counsel that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

User Access and Choice

Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us by emailing our Customer Support at [contact@newgistics.com](mailto:contact@newgistics.com?Subject=privacy).

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update or delete/remove your personal information by emailing our Customer Support at [contact@newgistics.com](mailto:contact@newgistics.com?Subject=privacy), or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain your information and the personal information we process on behalf of our clients for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services or the services of our clients. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and adhere to our agreements.

Opt-out Preferences

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails.

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here ](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)(or if located in the European Union [click here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Newgistics and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level.

Analytics/Log Files

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users’ movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in improving the Site, and to deliver content that is customized and personalized. IP addresses are not linked to personal information.

Security

This Site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. When you enter sensitive information (such as a User ID and password) on our service platform, we encrypt the transmission of that information using transport layer security (TLS). Your personal information is stored in secure, guarded facilities and is protected by a multi-layer cyber security program that includes firewalls, intrusion prevention (IPS), 24×7 monitoring and is only accessible by certain qualified employees of Newgistics. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect your private information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information.

Other Web Sites

Our Site contains links to other Web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another Web site for which Newgistics has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy policies on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.

Testimonials 

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our Site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [contact@newgistics.com](mailto:contact@newgistics.com?Subject=privacy).

Social Media Features and Widgets

Our Site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons and Widgets, such as the “share” button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients

We collect information under the direction of our clients, and often have no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data we process. We work with our clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning the purpose for which personal information is collected. If you are a customer of one of our clients and would no longer like to be contacted by such client, please contact that client directly. If you seek to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact you may need to direct your query to one of our clients, who is the data controller. If our client requests to remove your data we will respond to the request within 30 days.

In addition, Newgistics may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the user choice and access provisions of this Policy.

Changes to this Policy

Newgistics reserves the right to change this Policy at any time by posting a new policy at this location. We may update this Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. Any update will be effective immediately upon posting. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Contact Us

If you have questions about this Policy, you may contact us through the following:  
Newgistics, Inc.  
2700 Via Fortuna, Suite 300  
Austin, TX 78746  
Email: [contact@newgistics.com](mailto:contact@newgistics.com?Subject=privacy)
